David E. Lilienthal Papers, 1900-1981 (bulk 1950-1981 ): Inventory MC148
EADs for public policy collection from import batch
- Series 3: Correspondence and Related Materials, 1912-1949; 105 boxes; 2 items
  - Subseries 3E: 1939-1941, 10 boxes
    - Sparkman, John, 1941; 2 boxes
      - Re Speeches, 1941 January 14-November 14; 2 boxes
        - Little Rock, Arkansas. "The Development of a Region's Resources,", 1941 October 17; 1 box (Box 99)
        - University of Texas, Austin, Texas, 1941 November 14; 1 box (Box 99)
    - Stone, Irving, 1941; 1 box (Box 99)
    - Swope, Gerard, 1941; 1 box (Box 99)
    - Swope, Herbert Bayard, 1941; 1 box (Box 99)
    - Szold, H.J., 1941; 1 box
      - Tennessee Valley Authority, 1941; 1 box
        - Collective Bargaining, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 99)
        - Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 99)
        - Reappointment of David E. Lilienthal as Chairman, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 99)
        - Special Training Assignment by Norman Wengert, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 99)
    - Tennessee Valley Authority Act, 1941; 1 box (Box 99)
    - Wallace, Henry A, 1941; 1 box (Box 99)
    - White, William Allen, 1941; 1 box (Box 99)
    - Willkie, Wendell L, 1941; 1 box (Box 99)
    - Witte, Edwin E, 1941; 1 box (Box 99)
  - Subseries 3F: 1942-1944, 1914 September 24-1944; 8 boxes
    This subseries includes correspondence to and from Lilienthal in 1914-1944.
    - Allen, Forrest, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Arvin, Newton (Fred), 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Bauer, Harry C, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Blandford, John B, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Bradner, James W, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Brandeis, Elizabeth, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Brandeis, Fanny, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Brandeis, Louis, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Cavanah, Frances, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Chandler, Albert Benjamin, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Citron, Minna, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Clapper, Raymond, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Clark, Frank W, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Cooke, Morris L, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Crabtree, James, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Daniels, Jonathan, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Daniels, Josephus, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Davidson, Jo, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Davies, Joseph E, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Dorrance, Gordon, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Dorrance, Henry T, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Douglas, Paul H, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Douglas Aircraft Company, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Early, Stephen, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Emmert, James A, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Ernst, Morris L, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Evjue, William T, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Frankfurter, Felix, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Gaus, John M, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Glaeser, Martin G, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Gruening, Ernest, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Guthrie, Paul N, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Hedges, Marion H, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Herrick, Elinore, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Hopkins, Harry, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - King, Judson, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Krug, J.A., 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Lippmann, Walter, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Longden, Henry B, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - McGill, James H, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - McGinnis, Richard R, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - MacLeish, Archibald, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Marton, George, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Miller, Paul D, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Miscellaneous, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Morehouse, Edward W, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Nicely, James Mount, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Nichols, William I, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Norris, George W, 1942; 1 box (Box 100)
    - Owen, Kenneth, 1942; 1 box (Box 101)
    - Owen, Marguerite, 1942; 1 box (Box 101)
    - Oxnam, Bishop G. Bromley, 1942; 1 box (Box 101)
    - Pearson, Drew, 1942; 1 box (Box 101)
    - Pepper, Claude, 1942; 1 box (Box 101)
    - Rauschenbush, Mr. and Mrs. Paul, 1942; 1 box (Box 101)
    - Richberg, Donald R, 1942; 1 box (Box 101)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D, 1942; 1 box (Box 101)
    - Rosenman, Samuel I, 1942; 1 box (Box 101)
    - Ross, Malcolm, 1942; 1 box (Box 101)
    - Shih, Hu, 1942; 1 box (Box 101)
    - Smith, Florence, 1942; 1 box
      - Re Speeches, 1942 January 13-December 20; 1 box
        - American Institute of Cooperation, Atlanta, Georgia, 1942 January 13; 1 box (Box 101)
        - American Society for Public Administration, New York, New York, 1942 January 28; 1 box (Box 101)
        - Chattanooga Rotary Club, 1942 May 21; 1 box (Box 101)
        - Knoxville Kiwanis Club. "Politics and the Management of The Public's Business, 1942 July 9; 1 box (Box 101)
        - North Carolina Press Association, Asheville, North Carolina. "The Press Goes to War,", 1942 July 24; 1 box (Box 101)
        - Mobile, Alabama, Civic Organizations, 1942 July 28; 1 box (Box 101)
        - Decatur, Alabama, Chamber of Commerce, 1942 July 30; 1 box (Box 101)
        - CBS Broadcast, Remarks for Conference on Science, Philosophy and Religion, Columbia University, 1942 August 28; 1 box (Box 101)
        - Third Conference on Science, Philosophy and Religion, Columbia University, 1942 August 28; 1 box (Box 101)
          Includes correspondence with Bryson, Lyman; Finkelstein, Louis, etc.
        - TVA Employees. "TVA and the War", 1942 September 24; 1 box (Box 101)
        - Harvard University Seminar, 1942 November 20; 1 box (Box 101)
        - NBC Broadcast., Labor for Victor Program, 1942 December 20; 1 box (Box 101)
    - Swope, Gerard, 1942; 1 box (Box 101)
    - Tennessee Valley Authority: Miscellaneous, 1942; 1 box (Box 101)
    - Thompson, Dorothy, 1942; 1 box (Box 101)
    - Wallace, Henry A, 1942; 1 box (Box 101)
    - White, William Allen, 1942; 1 box (Box 101)
    - Willkie, Wendell L, 1942; 1 box (Box 101)
    - Allen, Forrest, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Arnold, Thurman W, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Arvin, Newton (Fred), 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Batt, William L, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Berle, Adolf A., Jr, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Bingham, Mrs. Barry, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Blandford, John B, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Bradner, James W, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Citron, Minna, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Claxton, Phil, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Currie, Lauchlin, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Daniels, Jonathan, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Dean, James W, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Emmert, James H, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Ernst, Morris L, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Evans, Llewellyn, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Finkelstein, Louis, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Fly, Lawrence, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Frankfurter, Felix, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Fromm, Erich, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Grauer, Ben, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Guess, Samuel, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Harvard Law Review, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Hopkins, Harry, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Hopkins, R.A., 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Kilgore, H.M., 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Lomax, Allen, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Longden, Henry B, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Longwell, Daniel, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Miscellaneous, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Morehouse, Edward W, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Morgan, Harcourt A, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Morgan, Harold V, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Nichols, William I, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Norris, George W, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Olds, Leland, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Owen, Kenneth, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Oxnam, Bishop G. Bromley, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Ramsey, D. Hiden, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Rauschenbush, Mrs. Paul, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Richberg, Donald R, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D, 1943; 1 box
      - Re Speeches, 1943 April 29-December 21; 1 box
        - West Kentucky Trip, 1943 April 29; 1 box (Box 102)
        - NBC Broadcast, "For This We Fight" Program, 1943 October 30; 1 box (Box 102)
        - Clarksville, Tennessee, Rotary Club, 1943 December 11; 1 box (Box 102)
        - Memphis, Tennessee, Rotary Club, "TVA - In War and Peace,", 1943 December 21; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Swidler, Joseph C., dates not examined; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Tennessee Valley Authority, dates not examined; 1 box
      - Re "Investigation of TVA" by the House Un-American Activities Committee in 1940, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 102)
      - Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 102)
      - S-702 Bill "For the Mobilization of the Scientific and Technical Resources of the Nation.", dates not examined; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Willkie, Wendell L, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Zink, Harold, 1943; 1 box (Box 102)
    - Agar, Herbert, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Allen, Forrest, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - American University, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Arvin, Newton (Fred), 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Bauer, Harry, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Beard, Charles A, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Berle, Adolf A., Jr, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Black, J K, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Bradner, James W, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Brandeis, Elizabeth, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Chase, Stuart: Concerning the Tennessee Valley Authority, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Chenery, William L, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Childs, Marquis, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Chinese Fan [Gift], 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Citron, Minna, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Claypool, James V, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Coghlan, Mr. and Mrs. Ralph C, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Comer, Donald, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Cooke, Morris L, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Daniels, Jonathan, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - de Schweinitz, Dorothea, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Dorrance, Gordon, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Douglas, Helen Gahagan, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Duffus, R.L., 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Duggan, Lawrence, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Ernst, Morris L, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Ethridge, Mark, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Evans, Llewellyn, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Evjue, William J, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Finkelstein, Louis, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Frankfurter, Felix, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - George, Harrison, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Gruse, Rev. W.P., 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Guess, Samuel, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Harburg, E.Y Yip, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Hill, Lister, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Hogate, Kenneth C, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Kai-Shek, Chiang, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Kaufman, Enit, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Kefauver, Estes, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Kern, Bishop Paul B, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Kirchwey, Freda, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Knopf, Alfred H, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Krug, J.A., 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Lewis, James, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Lichterman, Ira, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Lippmann, Walter, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Longden, Henry B, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Lorentz, Pare, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - McKellar, Kenneth D, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - MacLeish, Archibald, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Mann, Thomas, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Meyer, Eugene, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Milton, George F, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Miscellaneous, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Missouri Valley Authority and Other Watershed Developments, 1944; 1 box (Box 103)
    - Morehouse, Edward W, 1944; 1 box (Box 104)
    - Morgan, Harcourt A, 1944; 1 box (Box 104)
    - Moses, Robert, 1944; 1 box (Box 104)
    - Mumford, Lewis, 1944; 1 box (Box 104)
    - Nichols, William I, 1944; 1 box (Box 104)
    - Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1944; 1 box (Box 104)
    - Norris, George W, 1944; 1 box (Box 104)
    - Owen, Kenneth M, 1944; 1 box (Box 104)
    - Owen, Marguerite, 1944; 1 box (Box 104)
    - Oxnam., Bishop G. Bromley, 1944; 1 box (Box 104)
    - Patton, James G, 1944; 1 box (Box 104)
    - Phosphates, 1944; 1 box (Box 104)
    - Pinchot, Gifford, 1941 September 23-1944; 2 boxes
      - Publications by David E. Lilienthal, 1941 September 23-1944 October 10; 1 box
        - Survey Graphic. "Grand Job of Our Century,", 1944 August; 1 box (Box 104)
        - Nation. "Norris and the TVA", 1941 September 23; 1 box (Box 104)
        - Birmingham Age-Herald. Guest Column for John Temple Graves II, 1944 October 10; 1 box (Box 104)
        - Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 104)
        - TVA - Democracy on the March. Harper & Brothers, 1944: Correspondence with Publisher, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 104)
          Includes Some 1943 Materials.
      - TVA - Democracy on the March. Harper & Brothers, 1944: Correspondence: General, dates not examined; 1 box
        - (January - June), dates not examined; 1 box (Box 105)
        - (July - December), dates not examined; 1 box (Box 105)
    - Pulliam, Eugene C, 1944; 1 box (Box 106)
    - Rauschenbush, Mr. and Mrs. Paul, 1944; 1 box (Box 106)
    - Reed, Stanley, 1944; 1 box (Box 106)
    - Richberg, Donald R, 1944; 1 box (Box 106)
    - Richmond, Mrs. J.H., 1944; 1 box (Box 106)
    - Rogers, Alfred T, 1944; 1 box (Box 106)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D, 1944; 1 box (Box 106)
    - Rosenman, Samuel I, 1944; 1 box (Box 106)
    - Shelton, Barrett, 1944; 1 box (Box 107)
    - Shih, Hu, 1914 September 24-1944; 1 box
      - Re Speeches, 1914 September 24-1944 November 14; 1 box
        - Decatur, Alabama, Chamber of Commerce. "The Tennessee Valley: Region of Opportunity", 1944 January 4; 1 box (Box 107)
        - TVA Power Distributors Conference, Chattanooga, Tennessee, 1944 February 22; 1 box (Box 107)
        - Chattanooga, Tennessee, Kiwanis Club. "What Will Happen to the War Plants in the Tennessee Valley Region?", 1943 February 29; 1 box (Box 107)
        - Alabama State Federation of Labor, Sheffield, Alabama "The South's Stake in Labor,", 1944 April 17; 1 box (Box 107)
        - American Society of Planning Officials., Chicago, Illinois, 1944 May 1; 1 box (Box 107)
        - Neumann, Emanuel - Luncheon., New York, New York. Concerning the Jordan Valley Authority, 1944 June 16; 1 box (Box 107)
        - Paducah, Kentucky, 1944 June 29; 1 box (Box 107)
        - Mutual Broadcasting System., Washington D.C. "The TVA Belon s to All of America,", 1941 July 14; 1 box (Box 107)
        - League of Virginia Municipalities, Roanoke, Virginia, 1914 September 24; 1 box (Box 107)
        - Evansville, Indiana, Civic Organizations, 1944 October 12; 1 box (Box 107)
        - Murray State Teacher's College, Education Association, Murray, Kentucky, 1941 October 13; 1 box (Box 107)
        - Broadcast, North Dakota Farmers Union., Bismark, North Dakota, 1944 November 3; 1 box (Box 107)
        - Australian Broadcast, 1944 November 10; 1 box (Box 107)
        - Tennessee Farm Bureau., Nashville, Tennessee, 1944 November 14; 1 box (Box 107)
    - Sulzberger, Mrs. Arthur Hayes, 1944; 1 box (Box 107)
    - Swidler, Joseph C, 1944; 1 box
      - Tennessee Valley Authority, 1944; 1 box
        - Amendments to the TVA Act proposed by, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 107)
        - Kenneth D. McKellar and "Petition Opposing Proposed Amendments", dates not examined; 1 box (Box 107)
        - Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 107)
    - Thompson, Dorothy, 1944; 1 box (Box 107)
    - Towsley, Frank H, 1944; 1 box (Box 107)
    - Wallace, Henry A, 1944; 1 box (Box 107)
    - Willkie, Wendell L, 1944; 1 box (Box 107)
    - Winnet, Nochem S, 1944; 1 box (Box 107)
    - Yuying, Li, 1944; 1 box (Box 107)
    - Zanuck, Darryl F, 1944; 1 box (Box 107)
  - Subseries 3G: 1945-1946, 1933-1946; 11 boxes
    This subseries includes correspondence to and from Lilienthal in 1933-1946.
    - Alexander, Charles T, 1945; 1 box (Box 108)
    - Allen, Forrest, 1945; 1 box (Box 108)
    - Arvin, Newton (Fred), 1945; 1 box (Box 108)
    - Atomic Energy: General, 1945; 1 box (Box 108)
    - Atomic Energy Control: Hearings, 1945; 1 box (Box 108)
    - Atomic Energy Control Conference, University of Chicago, 1945 September 19-22; 1 box (Box 108)
    - Baker, John C, 1945; 1 box (Box 108)
    - Bankhead, John H, 1945; 1 box (Box 108)
    - Barkley, Alben W, 1945; 1 box (Box 108)
    - Barnard, Chester 1, 1945; 1 box (Box 108)
    - Bass, Basil N, 1945; 1 box (Box 108)
    - Blandford, John B, 1945; 1 box (Box 108)
    - Boardman, Philip, 1945; 1 box (Box 108)
    - Breckinridge, Frank P, 1945; 1 box (Box 108)
    - Bromfield, Louis, 1945; 1 box (Box 108)
    - Brownlow, Louis, 1945; 1 box (Box 108)
    - Canfield, Cass, 1945; 1 box (Box 108)
    - Chandler, I.V., 1945; 1 box (Box 108)
    - Chapman, Oscar L, 1945; 1 box (Box 108)
    - Chinese Fan [Gift], 1945; 1 box (Box 108)
    - Claypool, James V, 1945; 1 box (Box 108)
    - Coates, Albert, 1945; 1 box (Box 108)
    - Coghlan, Ralph C, 1945; 1 box (Box 108)
    - Cooke, Morris L, 1945; 1 box (Box 108)
    - Davenport, Marcia, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Davidson, Jo, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Dirksen, Everett, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Donaldson, Mrs. John W, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Douglas, Helen Gahagan, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Emmert, James A, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Ernst, Morris L, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Ervin, Charles W, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Evans, Llewellyn, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Frankfurter, Felix, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Grinnell, Leslie, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Harburg, E.Y. Yip, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Harris, Robert T, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Harvey, Peter, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Hill, Lister, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Isenbarger, Pat, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Kaufman, Enit, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Kefauver, Estes, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Kern, Bishop Paul B, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - King, Judson, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Knight, Harvey H, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Krug, J.A., 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Laski, Harold J, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
      Includes an Observation About Franklin D. Roosevelt Regarding David E. Lilienthal
    - Longden, Henry B, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Lord, Russell, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Lorentz, Pare, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - McGinnis, Richard R, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Miscellaneous, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Morgan, Harcourt A, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Nicely, James Mount, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Nichols, William I, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Owen, Marguerite, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Oxnam, Bishop G. Bromley, 1945; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Parker, Dorothy, 1945; 1 box
      - Re Publications by David E. Lilienthal, 1945 January 7-February 17; 1 box
        - New York Times Magazine "Shall We Have More TVA's?", 1945 January 7; 1 box (Box 109)
        - New Leader "The Grand Job of Our Century,", 1945 February 17; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Magazine Digest. "Will We Have a World TVA?, 1944-1945 October; 1 box
      - Progressive Farmer. "Atomic Energy and the People,", 1945 October; 1 box (Box 109)
      - TVA - Democracy on the March. Harper & Brothers, 1944; 1 box (Box 109)
    - Pulliam, Eugene C, 1945; 1 box (Box 110)
    - Radcliffe Quarterly., 1945 June 27; 1 box (Box 110)
      Includes Excerpts Prom a Commencement Address by David E. Lilienthal, 'Machines and the Human Spirit,'
    - Rauschenbush, Mrs. Paul, 1945; 1 box (Box 110)
    - Richmond, Mrs. J.H., 1945; 1 box (Box 110)
    - Robertson, John P. and Robertson, Hazel, 1945; 1 box (Box 110)
    - Rogers, Alfred T, 1945; 1 box (Box 110)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1945; 1 box (Box 110)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1933-1946.", 1945; 1 box (Box 110)
      Includes "Listing of TVA Correspondence with ... President
    - Roosevelt National Memorial Committee, 1945; 1 box (Box 110)
    - Rosenman, Samuel I, 1945; 1 box (Box 110)
    - Schacter, Harry, 1945; 1 box (Box 110)
    - Schlemmer, Fred C, 1945; 1 box (Box 110)
    - Schuster, M. Lincoln, 1945; 1 box (Box 110)
    - Sellar, Tim M, 1945; 1 box (Box 110)
    - Shelton, Barrett, 1945; 1 box (Box 110)
    - Sherwood, Robert E, 1945; 1 box (Box 110)
    - Smith, Lillian, 1945; 1 box
      - Re Speeches, 1945 January 5-October 25; 1 box
        - Pathe Newsreel., New York, New York, 1945 January 5; 1 box (Box 110)
        - Harvard University Economics Seminar, 1945 January 8; 1 box (Box 110)
        - Greensboro, North Carolina, Rotary Club, 1945 January 29; 1 box (Box 110)
        - North Carolina State College of Agriculture and Engineering, Raleigh, North Carolina, 1945 January 29; 1 box (Box 110)
        - North Carolina House of Representatives, 1945 January 30; 1 box (Box 110)
        - Carolina Political Union, Chapel Hill, North Carolina, 1945 January 30; 1 box (Box 110)
        - University of Mississippi, 1945 March 20; 1 box (Box 110)
        - Radio Forum, American Federation of Labor. "More TVA's?", 1945 March 25; 1 box (Box 110)
        - Society for Personnel Administration, 1945 March 26; 1 box (Box 110)
        - Hopkinsville, Kentucky, Civic Clubs, 1945 April 5; 1 box (Box 110)
        - Unversity of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, Conference on Research and Regional Welfare. "The Moral Responsibility of Research.,", 1945 May 11; 1 box (Box 110)
        - Dutch Treat Club, New York, New York_, 1945 May 29; 1 box (Box 110)
        - Southern Conference on Human Welfare - Luncheon in Honor of David E. Lilienthal. "New York and TVA: A Report to Stockholders,", 1945 June 4; 1 box (Box 110)
        - Radcliffe College, 'Machines and the Human Spirit,', 1945 June 27; 1 box (Box 110)
        - Federal Reserve Board., Chicago, Illinois, 1945 October 25; 1 box (Box 110)
    - Starnes, Joe, 1945; 1 box (Box 111)
    - Stokes, Thomas L, 1945; 1 box (Box 111)
    - Sulzberger, Mr. and Mrs. Arthur Hays, 1945; 1 box (Box 111)
    - Tead, Ordway, 1945; 1 box
      - Tennessee Valley Authority, 1945; 1 box
        - Atomic Energy, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 111)
        - Labor Relations, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 111)
        - Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 111)
        - Reappointment of David E. Lilienthal as Director: Oath of Office, May 22, 1945; Congratulatory Letters; News Items [A Sample], dates not examined; 1 box (Box 111)
    - Truman, Harry S, 1945; 1 box (Box 111)
    - Warburg, James P, 1945; 1 box (Box 111)
    - Wildman, Clyde E, 1945; 1 box (Box 111)
    - Yutang, Lin, 1945; 1 box (Box 111)
    - 1946, 1 box (Box 112)
    - Acheson, Dean, 1946; 1 box (Box 112)
    - Alba, Adolfo Orive, 1946; 1 box (Box 112)
    - Aleman, Miguel, 1946; 1 box (Box 112)
    - Allen, Forrest, 1946; 1 box (Box 112)
    - Allen, Frederic, 1946; 1 box (Box 112)
    - Arvin, Newton (Fred), 1946; 1 box (Box 112)
    - Atlantic Monthly, 1946; 1 box
      - Atomic Energy, 1946; 1 box
        - General, 1946; 1 box (Box 112)
        - International Control, 1946; 1 box (Box 112)
          Includes a Report an the International Control of Atomic Energy, March 16, 1946. By Department of State, Board of Consultants, David E. Lilienthal, Chairman; International Control of Atomic Energy, Growth of a Policy, Department of State; Clippings.
    - Atomic Energy Act of 1946, 1 box (Box 113)
    - Atomic Energy Commission: Appointment of David E. Lilienthal as Chairman by Harry S. Truman., October 28, 1946; Congratulatory Letters on Selection of David E. Lilienthal for Appointment as Chairman of the Atomic Energy Commission, 1 box (Box 113)
    - Atomic Energy Commission: Editorials and News clippings concerning the Selection of David E. Lilienthal for Appointment as Chairman of the Atomic Energy Commission, 1946; 1 box (Box 114)
    - Barnard, Chester I, 1946 June 20-24; 1 box (Box 114)
      Includes Letters to Lippmann, Walter from Chester I. Barnard
    - Baruch, Bernard M, 1946; 1 box (Box 114)
    - Bell, Ulric, 1946; 1 box (Box 114)
    - Bliven, Bruce, 1946; 1 box (Box 114)
    - Brandeis, Fanny, 1946; 1 box (Box 114)
    - Braucher, Howard, 1946; 1 box (Box 114)
    - British Atomic Energy Act, 1946; 1 box (Box 114)